ILR School Biography Files /4297
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILR School Biography Files
1948-2011
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations (NYSSILR)
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives
/4297
2 cubic feet
2 linear ft.
Case files, records (documents).
Biographical files on select ILR School faculty
8439264
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, June 30, 2014
EAD encoding:
Elizabeth Parker, May 08, 2023
Biographical / Historical
Founded in 1945 as the New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations, the ILR School today is advancing the world of work through teaching, research and outreach. ILR's mission is to prepare leaders, inform national and international employment and labor policy, and improve working lives, but as the world of work evolves, the school's focus broadens to keep pace with that change.
ILR studies many areas that shape the working world and contribute to an organization's success in a global economy. These include human resource management; labor-management relations; labor economics; organizational behavior; international and comparative labor; labor relations, labor law and history; conflict resolution; management development; diversity management; employment and disability; and social statistics.
An ILR education is grounded in the social sciences. Students and faculty explore and gain an understanding of human behavior through the lens of the workplace. Students also learn how organizations work and how they fit into the larger society and economy. As a result, they acquire knowledge and skills that help them to solve problems on-the-job and to build and manage productive work relationships. An ILR education, for students and professionals, is practical and applied.
ILR has more full-time faculty involved in teaching and research that spans the broad range of work and employment disciplines than any other educational institution of its kind. Its Martin P. Catherwood Library is regarded as the most comprehensive source of information in North America on work, employment and labor issues.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5619 PUBS: ACTWU Publications 5780 PUBS: ILGWU Publications 6000 PUBS: UNITE Publications 6200 PUBS: UNITE HERE Publications /4297 P: ILR School Biography Photographs
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives; New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations; Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America; Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union; Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees; UNITE HERE (Organization)
8439264
- John Abowd through Irving Ives (Box 1)
  - Records of Professor John Abowd, 1980-2004 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Professor Leonard Adams Bio, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Professor Lee Adler, Article Describing Research Work, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Daniel J. Alpern Memorial Scholarship Info, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Robert Aronson CV and Bio, 1952-1984 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Sam Bacharach, Research and CV, 2003-2006 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Stephen Barley, CV (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Stuart Basefsky, Excellence in Librarianship Award, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Rose Batt, Human Resources Scholarly Achievement Award, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Kenneth Beach Bio (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Professor John Bishop, CV, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - John Blanchard, Memorial Service, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Francine Blau, Articles, 2004-2009 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Isadore Blumen, Bio, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - George Borjas, CV, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - John Boudreau, Articles and CV, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - George Boyer, CV (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Robert Bretz, CV (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Vernon Briggs, CV & Articles, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Kate Bronfenbrenner, Articles, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Earl Brooks, Obituary, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - George Brooks, Articles, Retirement Party Announcement, 1983-1993 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Susanne Bruyere, Article, CV, Announcement of Hiring, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - John Bunge, Resume (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Temple Burling, Obituary, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - George Calvert, Announcement of Passing, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - James Campbell, Bio, CV, Obituary, 1952-1962 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Ralph Campbell, Article, Bio, Obituary, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Jesse Carpenter, Bio, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Martin Catherwood, Articles, Obituary, 1959-1978 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Cyrus Ching, Article (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Clark Gardner, Bio, Catalog of Records, 1950-2002 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Suzanne Cohen, Articles, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Lance Compa, Articles, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Alice Cook, Memorial Service, Articles, Awards, 1963-1993 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Maria Cook, Article, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Rudolph Corvini, Bio (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Jeff Cowie, Articles, 2002-2011 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Donald Cullen, CV, Bio, 1956-1987 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Cletus Daniel, Articles and Obituary, 2003-2010 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Philip Dankert, Excellence in Librarianship Award, Articles, Retirement Announcement, 2003-2004 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Ileen DeVault, CV, Article, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Donald Dietrich, Retirement Announcement and CV, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    Scope and Contents
    Per note in the folder, "the items in this folder are duplicates of material from /4417 box 5 ff 69"
  - Robert Doherty, Announcement of Deanship, Obituary, 1985-2005 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Ron Donovan, CV, Bio, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Lee Dyer, Articles, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Leone Eckert, Correspondence, Bio, Articles, 1948-1964 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Ronald Ehrenburg, Articles, Announcement of Appointment, 2003-2005 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Lynn Emerson, Bio, Retirement Announcement, 1948-1955 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Chris Erickson, CV (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Jennie Farley, Memorial, Obituary, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - R. Ferguson, Bio, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Gary Fields, Announcement of Hire, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Herbert Finch, Articles and Obituary, 1964-2005 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Felician Foltman, Articles, Obituary, Memorial, 1948-1994 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Matthew Freedman, Announcement of Hire, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Michael Gaffney, CV, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Walter Galenson, Announcement of Passing, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Rebecca Givan, Announcement of Hiring (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Barry Gerhardt, CV (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Michael Gold, Articles, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Cynthia Gramm, CV, Articles, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Alice Grant, Obituary, Articles, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Tributes to Alice Grant, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Lois Gray, CV, Articles, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - James Gross, Article, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Kate Griffith, Announcement of Hiring, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Leopold Gruenfeld, Catalog of Records, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Ali Hadi, CV (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Jennifer Halpern, Bio (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Tove Hammer, CV, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Maria Hanratty, Resume (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Kurt Hanslowe, Bio, Articles, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Gordon Law, Bio, Departure Notice, 1949-1983 (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Shirley Harper, Articles, Retirement Notice, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - George Hildebrand, Bio, CV, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Wayne Hodges, Article, Obituary, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Grace Horton, Obituary, Memorial, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Richard Hurd, Articles, CV, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - Robert Hutchens, Articles, CV, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - General ILR Faculty Articles, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - Ives Irving, Articles, Obituary (Box 1, Folder 82)
- J. James Jehring through Carolyn Zimmerman (Box 2)
  - James Jehring, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Vernon Jenson, 1973-1998 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Timothy A. Judge (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Lawrence Kahn, 1997-2004 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Harry Katz, 2003-2006 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Milton R. Konvitz, 1953-2003 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Henry Landsberger, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Gordon Law, 1983-1994 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Edward Lawlor, 1996-2004 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Risa Lieberwitz, 2004-2008 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - David Lipsky, 1995-2007 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Michael Lounsbury, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Duncan McIntyre, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Philomena Marquardt, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Ann Martin, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Philip McCarthy, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - John W. McConnell, 1948-1993 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Jean McKelvey, 1948-1973 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Robert B. McKersie, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - James McPherson, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Emil Mesics, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - George Milkovich, 1982-2004 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Frank B. Miller, 1959-2006 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - J. Gormly Miller, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Olivia Mitchell, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Francine Moccio, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - David Moore, 1943-1970 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - James Morris, 1957-1985 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Bernard G. Naas, 1964-2003 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Abraham Nash, 1972-1996 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Maurice Neufeld, 1942-1990 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Michael Nozzolio, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    Alum
  - Oscar Ornati, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Frances Perkins, 1957-1994 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Robert V. Pezdek, 1965-1970 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Vladimir Pucik (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Robert Raimon, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Charles M. Rehmus, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Effey Riley, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Robert F. Risley, 1949-1994 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Quinetta Robertson (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Ned Rosen (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Brian Runineau, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - S. Antonio Ruiz-Quintanilla, 1990-2004 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Jim Rundle, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Nick Salvatore, 1989-2009 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Woodrow J. Sayre, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Rocco Scanza, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Ron Seeber, 1988-2005 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Patrizia Sione, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Fred Slavick, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Alpheus W. Smith, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Robert Smith, 1988-2011 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Janet Sniezek, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - William Sonnenstuhl, 1989-2006 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Robert Stern, 1989-2001 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Richard Strassberg, 1973-2005 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Sean Sweeney, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Harrison Trice, 1955-1998 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Lowell Turner, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Anand Vidyashankar, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - William J. Wasmuth, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Theresa M. Welbourne (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Martin T. Wells (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Barbara Wertheimer, 1973-1984 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - William Foote Whyte, 1948-2000 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Lawrence K. Williams, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - John Windmuller, 1951-2010 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Charles Wrege, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Byron Yaffe, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Carolyn Zimmerman, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 71)